# 别人不用了的西瓜皮
Watermelon rinds that are often left out
# 然后冬瓜 凉瓜
and then winter melon, bitter melon
# 跟肉一搭 绝搭
complementing the meat. Perfect!
# 大爷您看排骨
Da Ye, please look at these pork ribs
# 这么点儿啊 够了大爷 不够吃
Only this tiny bit? It’s enough Da Ye. Not enough
# 别人不用的西瓜皮 冬瓜 凉瓜三瓜
Watermelon rinds that are not commonly used, winter melon and bitter melon, 3 kinds of melons
# 这里还一块鸡呢 我借点鲜味
Here’s a piece of chicken meat too, I need it’s umami flavour
# 还有一块鸡腿
And a piece of drumstick
# 还有两个白蔻 借点味
Two more white cardamoms, produce more aroma
# 两截葱 姜
Two pieces of spring onion and ginger
# 我今天是看着二伯做饭最猛的一次
I can see that Er Bai is putting a lot of effort today
# 乐什么 你别乐啊
Why are you smiling, don’t be so happy
# 我夸你两句你就乐啊
You are this happy even I just complimented you with a few sentences
# 然后再搁两块橘子皮
Add two pieces of mandarin peel
# 你看粤菜 你看人家煲冬瓜汤
In Cantonese cuisine, for winter melon soup,
# 咱们北方家庭里边都去皮
Us as northern China families would remove its rinds
# 到粤菜连瓤儿都不去
They would not even remove the flesh and the seeds
# 然后还带着冬瓜皮
And they left the rinds on it too
# 这瓤咱都留着煲水用
Well we keep the flesh to use during boiling the water
# 这凉瓜是两头发圆
This bitter melon has rounded ends
# 这苦瓜北方都是两头尖 长度也不算很长
Bitter melons in Northern China have more pointy ends, and they’re not really long
# 北方苦瓜比较苦 味儿重
Bitter melons in Northern China are more bitter with a more intense flavour
# 小魏 再搁点黄酒
Xiao Wei, please add some Huangjiu rice wine in it
# 去腥
Remove unpleasant smell
# 拿勺打打沫子
Remove the scum with a ladle
# 排骨也好了
The pork ribs are done
# 把这水给它倒了
Pour the water away
# 搁点水
Add some water
# 大爷为什么要让它洗干净了
Da Ye, why do we have to rinse it?
# 这意思说这汤不能浑浊
So that the soup is not cloudy
# 好 干净了
Ok, it's clean now
# 咱就搁这里头
We'll put it there
# 少搁点姜 陈皮来一点 葱
Put a little bit of ginger, some mandarin peel and spring onion
# 放胡椒粉 盐后搁
Add grounded white pepper then add the salt
# 少搁少搁 一会辣了 辣不了
Just put a tiny bit, or else it would be too spicy
# 黄酒
Huangjiu rice wine
# 这瓤不用扔 把这水煲一下
Don't throw away the flesh, boil the water together with it
# 这就是喝汤 煲十分钟
This is the soup we’ll be drinking, cook it for 10 minutes
# 水开了师父 上高压锅
The water is boiled, master. Pour it into high pressure cooker
# 地道啊 关火
It's authentic, turn off the flame
# 来 二十分钟
Here it goes, 20 minutes
# 下一步怎么着 调一个吃排骨的汁
What's the next step? Make a sauce for the pork ribs
# 香葱 香菜 小米辣
Scallions, cilantro and "Xiaomila" chili pepper
# 水开了师父 我给倒进去了
The water is boiled now master, I will add the melons into the wok
# 去一下瓜的苦味 三瓜下锅焯一下
# Remove the bitterness of the melons by blanching them for a while
# 切点小葱和香菜 咱们调一个汁
Cut some scallions and cilantro to make a sauce
# 焯完了迅速过凉
Cool them off immediately after blanching them
# 大爷您闻这清香味
Da Ye, can you smell the fragrance of it
# 各种瓜的味混合在一起
The fragrance of the melons are well mixed
# 三瓜为一体 变废为宝了
They complement each other well, turning waste into treasure
# 弄点豉油
Let's make some seasoned soy sauce
# 倒点葱油 这葱油非常香
Pour some scallion oil, it is very fragrant
# 我就省的煸葱了
I'll skip the step of frying the scallions
# 太香了
That's so aromatic
# 这（蒸鱼豉油）往里一倒一呲就行了
Heat up the seasoned soy sauce for seafood and pour it in, that's it
# 咱就等着排骨出锅了 豉油汁
We'll just wait for the pork ribs to be cooked
# 时间到了  手闪开师父
It's time now, please be careful with your hands master
# 大爷您看 清清凉凉的
Da Ye, please look at this, the soup is very clear
# 先把这排骨捞出来  正好
Take the pork ribs out first, they have been cooked until just right
# 高压锅出来的汤是清的
Soups cooked with high pressure cooker is very clear
# 因为它不是使劲咕嘟 没有大火翻腾
Because of the lower temperature, it doesn’t bubble vigorously
# 大爷咱把这加进去 三瓜搁上
Let’s add the melons in, three of them
# 调个味 盐
Season it, salt
# 压上 再压五分钟
Cook it for more 5 minutes
# 出锅了 您这三瓜
It can be served now, these melons
# 大爷给出盘呢
Da Ye is plating the dish
# 加汤
Add the soup
# 来俩枸杞 好了
Some goji berries, it's done
# 大爷 您先蘸这吃大爷
Da Ye, please try it with the dipping sauce first
# 大爷怎么样
How is it, Da Ye?
# 鲜
Strong umami flavour
# 蘸汁和不蘸汁截然不同
It's totally different with or without the dipping sauce
# 这排骨一点腥味都没有 肉香骨烂
The pork ribs don't have any gamey taste, aromatic meat and soft bone
# 西瓜皮 说实话这西瓜
To be honest, about the watermelon rinds
# 二伯应该去皮
Er Bai should’ve remove the outer skin
# 瓜皮要厚点大爷说了
Da Ye said that if the rinds are thicker,
# 这可以把皮削下去
We can just peel off the outer skin
# 因为今天这西瓜太薄了
Because the watermelon rinds are too thin
# 最后一个您再喝碗汤
Lastly, please drink a bowl of soup
# 好了 继续啊
Ok, let's continue
# 大家都在吃面
Everyone is having noodles
# 刚做好的面
They just made this
# 你知道这什么面么
Do you know what noodles is this
# 你说说
Say it out
# 你照照表
You can film the clock
# 十一点二十了
It's 11.20 p.m. already
# 还在工作
Still working
# 夜间十一点二十了
It's late night
# 再照照外边的黑天
Film the dark sky outside too
# 窗外十一点的天空
The sky of 11 o'clock outside the window
# 为什么您不吃面吃西瓜
Why don't you eat the noodles but the watermelon
# 我这老做做的我这嘴都木了
I’m always cooking, I don’t have the appetite already
# 做一天面了
We’ve been making noodles for all day long
# 大爷 您别在吃了
Da Ye, please don’t eat anymore
# 越吃越胖 那肚子
Your tummy is getting bigger and bigger
# 一会不还有那秘制鸡么
We still have the last dish yet to be served
# 秘制鸡最后真吃不动了
I don’t think I can eat much of that, the special made chicken
# 但总要尝一口
Nontheless, you still have to try a little bit of it
# 那秘制鸡还没蒸呢吧
The special made chicken is not done yet
# 这十二点了
It’s 12 o’clock now
# 让老四真说对了
Si Di is right